hometourseries.com 2018-10-06

# privacy policy - IKEA

We at IKEA North American Services LLC (IKEA) respect your concerns about privacy and value the trust you have placed in us. This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect, how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the information you provide to us. We tell you how you can reach us to update your contact information, remove your name from our mailing list, or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices. 

**What types of information does IKEA collect and use about me and how does IKEA use the information?**  
We collect and use information about you to communicate with you about our products, services and promotions. We also collect information to improve the shopping experience of IKEA consumers. Here are the ways we obtain information about you and the types of information we obtain. We also tell you how we use the information.

**Catalog**  
When you request a catalog from us, you provide us with contact information, such as your name, address, phone number and email address, so we may fulfill your request. To update your email communication preferences, or to unsubscribe, please [click here](http://info.ikea-usa.com/SignUp/).

**Email**  
When you subscribe to our email list, you provide us information such as your email address, name and ZIP code so we may communicate with you via email. We will send you email only if you have provided us with your email address and have asked us to communicate with you this way. If you've signed up to receive email from us, you'll continue to find IKEA in your inbox. It's quick and easy to review or [manage your email preferences.](http://info.ikea-usa.com/signup/Default.aspx) Please log in to let us know how we can communicate with you.

**Purchases**  
When you order or purchase an IKEA product, you may be required to give us contact and payment information (such as credit card information) so we may process your order. When you pay for an IKEA product using a credit card, we use your credit card information only to fulfill your order and for other internal purposes.

**Purchase verification policy**  
Please note that IKEA may request to verify your purchases against your receipt. Please keep your receipt available to show an IKEA representative upon request.

**IKEA FAMILY**  
If you sign up for IKEA FAMILY, you will be asked for your name, date of birth (to confirm eligibility) and information about how you wish to be contacted, such as email address, mobile phone number and home address.

**Customer Service**  
If you contact one of our customer service representatives, we may ask you for information such as your name, address and email address so we can respond to your questions or comments. With your consent, we may retain this information to personalize your experience with us and better assist you the next time you contact us.

**Help Us to Improve (HUTI)**  
In store we provide you with the option to leave a personal comment to the store manager. During this process you have the option to provide us with such information as your name, address, email address and telephone number so that we can respond to your questions or concerns. The information that is collected and retained by this unit is for IKEA's use only.

**Website**  
We collect information on our website using transient cookies, sometimes called session cookies. A transient cookie is a small file that contains information about a user, and disappears when the user's browser is closed. Unlike a persistent cookie, a transient cookie is not stored on the user’s hard drive; it is stored only in temporary memory that is erased when the web browser is closed. We use transient cookies to determine, for example, how you use our website so we can improve the design of our site. Transient cookies are not linked to any personally identifiable information about you. Cookies can be disabled in your web browser.

When you visit our web site, we also collect anonymous information from you. This includes the Internet browser you are using; the computer operating system you are using, time spent visiting the web site, usage patterns within the web site, and the domain name of the web site from which you linked to our site. This information is not matched to your personal information and does not personally identify you. We collect this information to help improve your experience on the web site. Additionally, IKEA may share account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with the law or protect our interests and property. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers or government agencies in connection with issues related to fraud or government subpoenas and warrants.

**FREE Hotspot Wireless Internet**  
IKEA USA provides a FREE Hotspot wireless internet Service in our IKEA stores provided by IKEA for use by customers of IKEA. All users are required to log-in individually as an independent user. [Click here to view our full FREE wireless internet terms and conditions](https://www.ikea.com/ms/en_US/privacy_policy/terms_conditions.html)

**Mobile**  
IKEA offers our customers the ability to find out what’s new at their local IKEA store through their mobile device, either by browsing our mobile web site or through text messaging. Usage of the mobile web site follows similar standards employed by our standard web site; cookies may be employed to remember preferences or previous activity but do not reveal personal information and can be disabled using your mobile device’s Internet options. For text messaging, users will only receive messages if they have specifically opted in for them; standard text message rates will apply. To join IKEA Mobile, text the keyword "JOIN" to 62345. **To unsubscribe from IKEA Mobile, text the keyword "STOP" to 62345**.

**Småland kid's play area**  
To take advantage of our supervised children’s play area while you shop, we require you to fill out a registration card that asks for the child’s name and age, the parent’s or guardian’s name, address, telephone number and signature, and any health concerns relating to the child that we should know. We ask for this information to help ensure the safety and security of the child.

**Other information you provide to us**  
Through surveys, you may provide us with information such as product preferences, reasons for purchasing a product, family and lifestyle information to help us learn more about your shopping preferences. You also may provide such information when you fill out a warranty card about a product you purchased from IKEA. In addition, you may give us such information if you register for or redeem IKEA special offers, discount coupons or other promotions.

We also may ask you to provide us with information about products that interest you and other lifestyle information. We will use such information to learn about your needs and preferences and if you choose to receive further communications from IKEA, to provide you with information about our products services and promotions.

**How may I indicate my privacy preferences?**  
Except as may be required in order to process a transaction, you may choose whether or not to give us your personal information, and if you do, how we use it. If we request your personal information, we will tell you why we are collecting it and seek your consent. Sometimes you will be asked to give your consent expressly (such as by checking a box or clicking on a web page). Other times we may obtain your consent implicitly by asking you to provide information with stated purposes but without any express statement of consent (such as when you order a product or request a catalogue). In other cases, your consent may be implied such as when you respond to a survey when it is understood that we will use the information to learn more about your needs and preferences, or your satisfaction as a customer so as to improve our products and services. In those cases your consent will be understood if you provide us with the requested information. You may notify us at any time that you do not wish us to use your information for any purposes that are not required to complete a transaction by contacting us in any of the ways described at the end of this Notice. You may at any time withdraw or change your consent to our use and disclosure of your information or request us to delete if from our files, subject to legal and contractual restrictions and requirements related to any transaction.

**How long does IKEA retain my information?**  
We retain your information as long as it is required for the purposes identified when you provided the information for such specific purposes or for any new purposes identified by us and consented to by you, and for any appropriate time thereafter including a sufficient time following to permit you to ask any questions regarding its use. Your contact information which you provide through the customer profile process (described above) is retained until you request us to delete or change it. Information which is created as part of your shopping experience, such as shopping lists, price offers, personal planners and designs, is retained for varying periods up to two years. Certain information is retained for longer periods for our internal audit and quality control purposes.

**Does IKEA share the information it obtains about me with third parties?**  
IKEA does not share personal information about its consumers with any third parties outside the IKEA corporate family for their own marketing purposes. However, we may do so within the IKEA corporate family. We do share this information with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf, but these service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. We also may disclose information about you as required by law.  
We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. If the business is transferred, we will provide you with the opportunity to tell us that you would prefer that information about you not be transferred. Should such a transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses personal information about you in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice.

**How does IKEA protect personal information?**  
The security of personal information is a high priority for us. We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration and destruction of the personal information in our possession. We are committed to providing appropriate security controls to protect personal information we have about you against foreseeable hazards.

**Does IKEA process my information outside of the U.S.?**  
We may transfer your information outside of the United States for processing and storing. The privacy laws in other jurisdictions may differ from United States privacy laws and in some jurisdictions your information may be accessed by law enforcement authorities or the courts. If you would like to obtain more information about our policies and practices relating to our transfer and processing information outside of the United States, please contact us in any of the ways described below under “How can I contact IKEA?”.

**How does IKEA update its Privacy Notice?**  
IKEA services and promotions will change over time. This Privacy Notice will be updated periodically to reflect those changes and corresponding changes in our information practices. Whenever we revise this Privacy Notice, we will change the date on the notice to indicate when the revisions were made. We reserve the right to change our information practices and the terms of this Privacy Notice, and to apply the changed practices to all information we have about you. By using this web site, you agree to accept the terms of this Privacy Notice as stated at the time you use it. Any future access to this web site subsequent to the posting of a revised Privacy Notice will be deemed to be your acceptance of this Privacy Notice as then revised. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Notice at any time.

**Does the IKEA website contain links to other websites?**  
The IKEA website may contain links to other websites that operate independently of IKEA and are not under our control. We provide links to other websites solely for your convenience and information. Other websites may have their own privacy notices, which we suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. IKEA is not responsible for information that is provided by, or collected through, those websites or for any other use of those websites.

**How can I update my personal information and privacy preferences?**  
We recognize that having accurate and up-to-date information about you and your preferences is important to our ability to properly serve your interests. Please log in to update your email contact information by [clicking here](http://info.ikea-usa.com/signup/default.aspx?login=1).

**Will I receive email from IKEA?**  
We will send you email only if you have provided us with your email address and have asked us to communicate with you this way. 

IKEA also occassionally sends emails to customers who have opted in to receive emails from third parties. To unsubscribe from these communications, simply click on the unsubscribe link located within the email and you will be able to unsubscribe from the list owner.

**What if I prefer not to receive communications from IKEA?**  
If you prefer not to receive product information or promotions from us by U.S. Mail, please [click here](http://info.ikea-usa.com/signup/mailOptout.aspx). To unsubscribe from our email list, please follow the opt-out instructions at the bottom of the email you received, or log in to [manage your email preferences](http://info.ikea-usa.com/signup/default.aspx?login=1) and update your profile by deselecting "Please send me: Inspirational emails and updates."

**How can I contact IKEA?**  
If you have any other questions about IKEA's privacy practices or about your personal information, please [contact us here](https://www.ikea.com/ms/en_US/customer_service/contact_us/contact.html) call  
1-888-888-4532,  
or write us at:  
IKEA North America Services, LLC  
Attention: Privacy Notice  
420 Alan Wood Rd  
Conshohocken, PA 19428

We will respond to your inquiry or investigate your concern as quickly as possible.

DATED: December 9, 2015
